# **Samuel King**

#### LinkedIn | GitHub

A responsible and motivated Software Engineer. Experience building enterprise web applications in the Professional Services and E-commerce space. A skilled communicator and team player, comfortable integrating into new teams and working to deliver timely and effective solutions.

## **Relevant Experience**

#### Sainsbury's Tech, Software Engineer (May 2021 - present)

Working in the Shared Services team to implement a microservice architecture to replace a legacy monolith, serving downstream tech teams.

- Delivery of event driven microservice architecture using Kafka message broker
- Implementation of eventstore library for NestJS as a key dependency for set of microservices
- Involvement with business stakeholders to gather requirements and communicate the features of the new system
- Present regularly at team knowledge share sessions, advocate for continuous improvement and use of agile methodologies

Tools and technologies: NestJS, React, TypeScript, GraphQL, Gremlin, Avro, Kafka, Postgres, MongoDB, Docker

#### Accenture, Software Engineer (October 2019 - May 2021)

- · Build e-commerce solution to meet client needs, working full-stack using JavaScript technologies
- Implementation of various full-stack features, building UI components, development and consumption of REST endpoints, third-party integrations
- Sole responsibility for design and implementation of end-to-end performance test solution: writing test scripts, configuration and deployment of test environment, and automation of scheduled test runs
- Facilitation of weekly Engineering Guild forum. Delivery of regular presentations to guild of 40+ engineers, senior management, and client stakeholders

Tools and technologies: React, Redux, TypeScript, GraphQL, Node.js, Jest, AWS Lambda, Elasticsearch, JMeter, BlazeMeter, Jenkins

### Caterpillar, Graduate Engineer (September 2018 - September 2019)

- Process improvement projects lead, working with internal and external stakeholders
- Responsible for design and development of new and existing hardware

#### Ricardo, Undergraduate Engineer (July 2015 - July 2016)

• Delivery of major software features on commercial automotive design application (Java)

Tools and technologies: Java, MATLAB

# Volunteering

### Onja, Volunteer Career Counsellor (June 2021 - present)

- A social enterprise in Madagascar that trains capable, low-income youth into frontend developers
- Conducting mock interviews on a weekly basis to prepare students for their first developer roles

## **Education**

## Makers Academy (October 2019 - December 2019)

- Intensive 12-week web development course at Makers Academy in London
- Pair programming, team projects, TDD, agile methodologies, OOP

## Cardiff University (September 2013 - July 2018)

• MEng, Mechanical Engineering, First Class Honours

## **Hobbies and Interests**

- Keen cyclist: completed several self-supported bike rides, most recently a 270 mile ride in 24 hours from London to Paris (2019), and a 1,000 mile ride from Berlin to Cardiff in 2018
- Triathlon: train and compete in various distances, most recently completed IRONMAN 70.3 Weymouth

# **Side Projects**

• Web development blog <a href="mailto:sk52.github.io">sk52.github.io</a> - a Gatsby starter blog used as a testing ground for learning new things, and then writing about them as blog posts.

## LinkedIn

To find out more about my experience or to get in touch, find me on LinkedIn